<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xlingpaper PUBLIC "-//XMLmind//DTD XLingPap//EN"
"XLingPap.dtd">
<xlingpaper
version="2.24.0"
><styledPaper
><lingPaper
automaticallywrapinterlinears="yes"
version="2.28.0"
><frontMatter
><title
><object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> User Documentation</title
><author
>H. Andrew Black</author
><affiliation
>SIL International</affiliation
><emailAddress
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</emailAddress
><date
>28 February, 2022</date
><version
>Version 0.9.0 Alpha</version
><version
>Copyright © 2021-2022 SIL International</version
><contents
></contents
></frontMatter
><section1
id="sIntro"
><secTitle
>Introduction</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> is a tool to edit <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> grammar files. It is designed to help you see the grammar file items more easily. Eventually, we hope to make it even show things like the feature system implied within the grammar file</p
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> looks like what is shown in <exampleRef
letter="xSample"
num="xSample"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xSample"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='650' "
src="resources/PcPatrEditor.png"
width="450"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The file name of the grammar file is shown in the upper left part of the window. You edit the grammar in the main pane.</p
><p
>You can drag the edges of the window to make it larger.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sEditMenu"
><secTitle
>Edit menu items</secTitle
><p
>The <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Edit</object
> menu item has the standard set of options such as copy, cut and paste. It also allows you to undo and redo changes. There are two other items as described below.</p
><section2
id="sFindReplace"
><secTitle
>Find/Replace</secTitle
><p
>Using the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Find/Replace</object
> item brings up the Find/Replace dialog. It looks something like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xFindReplace"
num="xFindReplace"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xFindReplace"
><chart
><img
src="resources/FindReplace.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>It is fairly straightforward. The “Incremental” option can be used to have <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> search for the text in the “Find:” box as you type.</p
><p
>Some things to note about how this dialog box works:</p
><ol
><li
>Using the “Selection” option will search within whatever text you currently have selected. It will only find any item once (because it loses the selection when it selects what it found).</li
><li
>The “Whole word” option will fail if you try and find any combination of letters (and numbers) with something else (e.g., a minus sign).</li
><li
>If the item found is off to the right of the window (i.e., you need to scroll to the right in order to see it), that found item will not be visible (but will be selected). It may work better if you set the <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> window to be full screen.</li
><li
>The “Replace All” process does not work when the “Selection” option is set.</li
></ol
><p
>For information on how to use a regular expression to find (and replace), see <link
href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html"
>https://​docs.​oracle.​com/​javase/​8​/docs​/api​/java​/util​/regex/​Pattern.html</link
>. If <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> finds an error in the syntax of a regular expression in either the find or replace fields, an error message in red will be shown. Hopefully, it will give you enough information to know how to fix the problem.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sFindNext"
><secTitle
>Find next</secTitle
><p
>You can use the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Find next</object
> item to repeat whatever the last find/replace operation was. There will be an audible beep if cannot go to the next item.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sGoToLine"
><secTitle
>Go to line</secTitle
><p
>Using the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Go to line</object
> item brings up a chooser that looks like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xGoToLine"
num="xGoToLine"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xGoToLine"
><chart
><img
src="resources/GoToLine.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>Enter the line number and click the “OK” button. That line number will be shown.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sComments"
><secTitle
>Comments</secTitle
><p
>When you select a portion of text, you can insert (or remove) the comment character at the beginning of each line in the selected portion. If the selected text does not start at the beginning of a line, a comment character will still be inserted (or removed) at the beginning of that text material.</p
><p
>To insert comments in selected material, use either <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Edit / Insert comment</object
> or type <object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl-Shift-C</object
>. To remove comments in selected material, use either <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Edit / Remove comment</object
> or type <object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl-Shift-R</object
>.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sBookmarksMenu"
><secTitle
>Bookmarks menu items</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> has an ability for you to mark certain lines with bookmarks. You can then move quickly from one bookmark to another. <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will remember your bookmarks for each grammar file.<endnote
id="nBookmarkMemory"
><p
>This is done on a machine-by-machine basis. That is, if you use <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> on one computer and then copy a grammar file to another computer, the second computer will not know where the bookmarks are. You will have to create the bookmarks again. (On Windows, the bookmarks are stored in C:\ProgramData\SIL\PcPatrEditor\bookmarks.xml; on Linux and Mac OS X, they are in ~/.pcpatreditor/bookmarks.xml.)</p
></endnote
></p
><p
>To toggle a bookmark, use either <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Bookmarks / Toggle bookmark</object
> or type <object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl-F2</object
>. To go to the next bookmark, use either <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Bookmarks / Next bookmark</object
> or type <object
type="tKey"
>F2</object
>. To go to the previous bookmark, use either <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Bookmarks / Previous bookmark</object
> or type <object
type="tKey"
>Alt-F2</object
>. When moving from one bookmark to another, if there are no more bookmarks in that direction, <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will automatically wrap to the next appropriate bookmark.</p
><p
>If you wish to remove or clear all bookmarks, use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Bookmarks / Clear all bookmarks</object
>.</p
><p
>When a line has a bookmark set for it, there will be a tag-like icon before the line number. It might look like line 9 in example <exampleRef
letter="xBookmark"
num="xBookmark"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xBookmark"
><chart
><img
src="resources/bookmark.png"
></img
></chart
></example
></section1
><section1
id="sTools"
><secTitle
>Tools menu item</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> currently has one tool option.</p
><section2
id="sExportSelected"
><secTitle
>Export selected rules for debugging</secTitle
><p
>This tool option is available under the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Tools</object
> menu item as <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Export selected rules for debugging</object
>. This is useful when you are trying to debug a <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> grammar file and want to create a separate grammar file that contains only selected rules.</p
><p
>When you invoke this option, <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will bring up a dialog box containing a list of the rules. In one grammar file, it looked like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xRuleSelector"
num="xRuleSelector"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xRuleSelector"
><chart
><img
src="resources/RuleSelector.png"
width="500"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>For each rule, it has a check box, the phrase structure rule and the rule identifier. You select which rules you want to export by clicking on them. (You can also use the up and down arrows and the space bar to select/deselect rules).</p
><p
>When you have chosen the rules you want to use, click on the “OK” button. <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will ask you to save the file, giving it a new name. This new file will contain all of the templates but just the selected rules.</p
><p
>See section <sectionRef
sec="sAfterExport"
></sectionRef
> for what the options are for what happens next after saving the file containing the selected rules.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sReports"
><secTitle
>Reports menu items</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> currently has two report options.</p
><section2
id="sConstituents"
><secTitle
>Show phrase structure constituents</secTitle
><p
>This report option is available under the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Reports</object
> menu item as <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Show phrase structure constituents</object
>. This is useful when you want to see what the current set of non-terminal and terminal constituents are.</p
><p
>When you invoke this option, <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will bring up a dialog box showing the non-terminals and terminals. In one grammar file, it looked like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xConstituentsDialog"
num="xConstituentsDialog"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xConstituentsDialog"
><chart
><img
src="resources/ConstituentsDialog.png"
width="500"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>Unlike most dialog boxes, you can still edit the grammar, etc., in the main program. Note, however, that it shows the set of constituents at the time the report was generated. If you make changes after that, you will need to invoke the report again. We suggest you close the older dialog first.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sFeatureSystem"
><secTitle
>Show feature system</secTitle
><p
>This report option is available under the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Reports</object
> menu item as <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Show feature system</object
>. This is useful when you want to see what feature paths are used throughout the grammar, arranged as a system. Sometimes it will show typos you had not noticed before.</p
><p
>When you invoke this option, <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will bring up a dialog box showing the feature system. In one grammar file, it looked like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xFeatureSystemDialog"
num="xFeatureSystemDialog"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xFeatureSystemDialog"
><chart
><img
src="resources/FeatureSystemDialog.png"
width="500"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>Unlike most dialog boxes, you can still edit the grammar, etc., in the main program. Note, however, that it shows the feature system at the time the report was generated. If you make changes after that, you will need to invoke the report again. We suggest you close the older dialog first.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sSettings"
><secTitle
>Settings menu items</secTitle
><p
>The <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings</object
> menu item has several options you can use to (hopefully) improve your experience with using <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
>. These are described below.</p
><p
>Please note that these settings are associated with the <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> program on your computer. Once you set them, they will be used each time you use <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> (until you change them, of course).</p
><section2
id="sArrowKeysShowMatching"
><secTitle
>Show matching parentheses, braces, brackets, and/or wedges with arrow keys</secTitle
><p
>Whenever you key an opening parenthesis ('<object
type="tSynTagmeme"
>(</object
>'), brace ('<object
type="tSynTagmeme"
>{</object
>'), bracket ('<object
type="tSynTagmeme"
>[</object
>'), or wedge ('<object
type="tSynTagmeme"
>&lt;</object
>'), <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will automatically insert the matching closing item.</p
><p
>There are times when you need to see the matching items For this reason, there is the first item under the main <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings</object
> menu item: <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Show matching items with arrow keys</object
>. When this is checked, whenever you use an arrow key to cross over a parenthesis (or brace or bracket or wedge) in the grammar, <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will temporarily select the item that matches the one crossed over.</p
><p
>Besides using this menu option, you can also use the toolbar button shown in <exampleRef
letter="xShowMatchingParensArrows"
num="xShowMatchingParensArrows"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xShowMatchingParensArrows"
><table
border="1"
><tr
><th
align="center"
>Show matching with arrows</th
><th
align="center"
>Do not show matching with arrows</th
></tr
><tr
><td
XeLaTeXSpecial="valign-fixup='-3pt'"
align="center"
><img
src="resources/ShowParensPressed.png"
></img
></td
><td
XeLaTeXSpecial="valign-fixup='-3pt'"
align="center"
><img
src="resources/ShowParensNotPressed.png"
></img
></td
></tr
></table
></example
></section2
><section2
id="sDelayMatching"
><secTitle
>Delay to use when showing matching parentheses</secTitle
><p
>The second item under the main <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings</object
> menu item is <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Delay to use when showing matching items</object
>. The default delay is 750 milliseconds (i.e., three quarters of a second). Depending on your typing speed, you may want to change this value. Use this menu item to change the delay value to be shorter or longer. The shortest allowed value is 125 milliseconds (i.e., one eighth of a second) and the longest value allowed is 4000 milliseconds (i.e., 4 seconds).</p
></section2
><section2
id="sSyntagmemeFontSize"
><secTitle
>Font size for the grammar</secTitle
><p
>The third item under the main <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings</object
> menu item is <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Font size</object
>. This lets you set the font size for the text of the grammar file.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sAfterExport"
><secTitle
>Action to take after exporting selected rules</secTitle
><p
>The fourth item under the main <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings</object
> menu item is <object
type="tMenuItem"
>After export</object
>. This lets you choose what you want <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> to do after you have saved a new grammar file for debugging. See section <sectionRef
sec="sExportSelected"
></sectionRef
>.</p
><p
>When you hover over <object
type="tMenuItem"
>After export, </object
> three possible actions are shown:</p
><ol
><li
><object
type="tMenuItem"
>Continue editing in the current file</object
></li
><li
><object
type="tMenuItem"
>Open the exported file</object
></li
><li
><object
type="tMenuItem"
>Open the exported file in a new instance</object
></li
></ol
><p
>The one with a check mark by it is the currently selected one.</p
><p
>The first one is the default option. The third one will open yet another instance of the <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> that has the exported file in it. This way you can still see the original file (in one instance of the <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
>) as well as the exported file.</p
><p
>To select one of the options, merely click on it.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sFeaturePathSearching"
><secTitle
>Feature path searching</secTitle
><p
>At any point while editing, you can type <object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl-space</object
> or right-click the mouse and <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will show you a dialog box like the one in example <exampleRef
letter="xFeaturePathSearch"
num="xFeaturePathSearch"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xFeaturePathSearch"
><chart
><img
src="resources/FeaturePathSearch1.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>As you type, it will show all feature paths that match what you type.  When you click on “OK” or hit the <object
type="tKey"
>Enter</object
> key, <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> will insert the text of the full path you have chosen into the grammar at the point of the text cursor.</p
><p
>There are two possible ways to search the list of feature paths.  The default is to search from the beginning of the path.  The other is to search for any part of a path that matches part of what is typed in the box.</p
><p
>The fifth item under the main <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings</object
> menu item is <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Feature path searching</object
>. This lets you choose which option you want <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> to use when typing in the box.</p
><p
>When you hover over <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Feature path searching, </object
> the two possible actions are shown:</p
><ol
><li
><object
type="tMenuItem"
>From the beginning</object
></li
><li
><object
type="tMenuItem"
>Anywhere</object
></li
></ol
><p
>The one with a check mark by it is the currently selected one.</p
><p
>The first one is the default option.</p
><p
>To select one of the options, merely click on it.</p
></section2
><section2
contentType="ctNotNow"
id="sInterfaceLanguage"
><secTitle
>Change the interface language</secTitle
><p
>You can set the user interface language by using the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Settings / Change the interface language</object
> menu item. This brings up a dialog box showing the current interface language in a drop down chooser. Click on the chooser's drop down button to see other interface language choices. The choices given use the name of the language in the current interface language (so if the current interface language is English, then it will show “Spanish” as an option; if the current interface language is Spanish, it will show English as “inglés”).</p
><p
>The current version has English, French and a rough, most likely often inaccurate version of Spanish. Any corrections to the Spanish are welcome.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
contentType="ctNotNow"
id="sErrorMessage"
><secTitle
>Error messages</secTitle
><p
>Whenever you process a tree description, if <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> notices any error in the description, it will show the error message in the same place where the tree diagram usually appears. The message tries to indicate what the problem is and where it was found (in terms of line number and character position). It also shows where in the tree description the error was found. While these messages are intended to be helpful, sometimes it may be the case that what needs to be done to fix the error is not necessarily what the message implies will fix it.</p
><p
>For example, when the message is about a missing closing parenthesis, the message actually indicates the innermost place where the outer parentheses match. So it may not be the best place to insert a closing parenthesis; but, on the other hand, it may work just fine. You may want to use the arrow keys to find the best place to fix the problem (see section <sectionRef
sec="sArrowKeysShowMatching"
></sectionRef
>).</p
><p
>Another thing to note is that for longer, more complicated tree descriptions, it may take a 2-3 times longer for the tree drawing process to happen if it finds an error.</p
><p
>Example <exampleRef
letter="xErrorTypes"
num="xErrorTypes"
></exampleRef
> lists the error types <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> reports along with a brief description of what the error type might mean.</p
><example
num="xErrorTypes"
><table
border="1"
><tr
><th
width="2in"
>Error Type</th
><th
width="3.25in"
>Meaning</th
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Missing closing parenthesis</object
></td
><td
>At least one closing parenthesis is missing.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Missing content after subscript</object
></td
><td
>There is a subscript symbol but there is not content after it. See sections.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Missing content after superscript</object
></td
><td
>There is a superscript symbol but there is not content after it. See sections.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Missing opening parenthesis</object
></td
><td
>An opening parenthesis needs to be inserted. This can happen when there is a node with content followed by a node type or a line type. See sections .</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Syntax error in description</object
></td
><td
>Perhaps obviously, this indicates some kind of error, but <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> failed to identify it. Look at where it was found and see if you can guess what might be wrong.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>There is content after a completed tree</object
></td
><td
>A “completed tree” means that there is a matching closing parenthesis for the first opening parenthesis. This error indicates that some content or nodes occur after the closing parenthesis which matches the first opening parenthesis. It may be that you need another opening parenthesis before the first opening parenthesis or maybe some content was keyed in the wrong place at the end.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Too many closing parentheses</object
></td
><td
>A closing parenthesis was found that does not have a matching opening parenthesis.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Too many line types</object
></td
><td
>Only one line type is allowed in a node. See section .</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Too many node types</object
></td
><td
>Only one node type is allowed in a node. See section .</td
></tr
></table
></example
></section1
><section1
id="sKnownProblems"
><secTitle
>Known problems</secTitle
><p
>The following items are known to be less than desirable with this version of <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
>:</p
><ul
><li
>When exporting selected rules or showing constituents, there will probably be a pause before the dialog comes up. We would like to have the mouse cursor have the “wait” shape during this processing, but have not figured out how to do it.</li
><li
>When you are using bookmarks and export selected rules with the “Open the exported file in a new instance” option, the bookmarks of the original file may be stored as the bookmarks for the exported file.</li
><li
>When showing matching parentheses while using arrow keys (see section <sectionRef
sec="sArrowKeysShowMatching"
></sectionRef
>), if you type several arrow keys quickly, the cursor caret may not be where you expect it. Either<ul
><li
>turn off the show matching parentheses with the arrow keys option;</li
><li
>set the delay to be shorter (see section <sectionRef
sec="sDelayMatching"
></sectionRef
>); or</li
><li
>wait for the matching parenthesis to show before pressing the next arrow key.</li
></ul
></li
></ul
></section1
><section1
id="sSupport"
><secTitle
>Support</secTitle
><p
>If you have any questions with <object
type="tPcPatrEditor"
></object
> or find bugs in it, please send an email to <link
href="mailto:blackhandrew@gmail.com"
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</link
>.</p
></section1
><backMatter
><endnotes
></endnotes
><references
></references
></backMatter
><languages
><language
id="lVernacular"
name="vernacular"
></language
><language
id="lGloss"
name="gloss"
></language
><language
id="en"
></language
><language
font-family="Ezra SIL"
id="lHebrew"
></language
><language
color="black"
font-family="Courier New"
id="lTreeExample"
></language
></languages
><types
><comment
>The following types are provided as pre-set examples. You may well want to create your own types that refer to one or more of these. You do that by typing in the names of the types in the types attribute of your type.</comment
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tBold"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
id="tBoldItalic"
></type
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tEmphasis"
></type
><type
id="tGrammaticalGloss"
types="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
id="tItalic"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-variant="normal"
id="tNoSmallCaps"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-underline&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:overline"
id="tOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-style="normal"
font-variant="normal"
font-weight="normal"
id="tRegular"
></type
><type
font-family="Charis SIL Small Caps"
id="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="line-through"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:line-through"
id="tStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="subscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:sub;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSubscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='sub'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="superscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:super;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSuperscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='super'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="underline"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:underline"
id="tUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;underline&quot;"
></type
><comment
>Add your custom types here.</comment
><type
id="tDialogTitle"
></type
><type
color="#800080"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
font-style="italic"
id="tEmpty"
></type
><type
color="red"
id="tErrorType"
></type
><type
color="blue"
font-family="Arial"
id="tGloss"
></type
><type
color="#009900"
font-family="Charis SIL"
font-weight="bold"
id="tKey"
></type
><type
color="red"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tLexical"
></type
><type
before="PcPatr"
color="navy"
id="tPcPatr"
></type
><type
before="PcPatrEditor"
color="navy"
id="tPcPatrEditor"
></type
><type
color="maroon"
id="tMenuItem"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tNonterminal"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Monospaced"
font-weight="bold"
id="tSynTagmeme"
></type
><type
color="navy"
id="tTool"
></type
></types
><contentControl
><contentTypes
><contentType
id="ctKeyColor"
>Tree description in color/font</contentType
><contentType
id="ctRegular"
>Tree description plain</contentType
><contentType
id="ctNotNow"
>Not now</contentType
></contentTypes
><contentControlChoices
><contentControlChoice
active="no"
exclude="ctKeyColor"
>Tree description regular</contentControlChoice
><contentControlChoice
active="no"
>Tree description color/font</contentControlChoice
><contentControlChoice
active="yes"
exclude="ctNotNow"
>Not now</contentControlChoice
></contentControlChoices
></contentControl
></lingPaper
><xi:include
href="SILInternationalPaperStylesheet.xml"
xpointer="element(/1)"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
></xi:include
></styledPaper
></xlingpaper
>
